{"tossups": [{"question": "In this novel, a man is told, \"We're widows...There's little can be hidden from us now,\" after a group of hags he refers to as \"ladies\" accost him for failing to do his duty as he rides his horse Horace. This novel's final chapter is narrated by a boatman who can only ferry one person at a time to a mysterious island. In this novel, memories of a kind red-haired woman and the disappearance of the girl Marta are among the \"puzzling episodes\" that trouble an old man. Towards the end of this novel, a warrior vows to raise a boy as an instrument of racial vengeance after earlier saving him from an ogre attack on a village. In this novel, Sir Gawain is sworn to protect the dragon Querig because the mist of forgetfulness that Querig produces allows the Saxons and Britons to live together. For 10 points, name this 2015 fantasy novel in which the elderly couple Axl and Beatrice search for their long-lost son, written by Kazuo Ishiguro.", "answer": "The Buried Giant", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Buried Giant</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Buried Giant"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "James and Jorndorf dispute Jansenist readings of this play, citing the lines \"You are in love. We cannot change our destiny,\" as evidence of un-Christian fatalism. In this play's preface, its author justifies its genre, calling it \"a school in which virtue was taught not less well than in the schools of the philosophers.\" A character in this play asserts that \"the day is not purer than the depths of my heart\" after his abandoned sword is used to accuse him of a crime. Another character in this play mourns her six dead brothers killed by her lover's father, who adopts her as his daughter in its final line. The first line in this play, \"I am leaving,\" is spoken to Theramenes (thair-uh-MEE-nees) by a man who wants to escape Troezen (\"treason\") and is in love with Ismene's (iz-MEE-nee's) friend Aricia. In this play's final act, that man is killed by a half-bull, half-dragon creature sent by Neptune, and Oenone (ee-NOH-nee) drowns herself over the guilt of having falsely accused him of raping his stepmother, who admits his innocence as she dies by poison. For 10 points, name this French tragedy about the title character's love for Theseus's son Hippolytus, a work by Jean Racine.", "answer": "Phe\u0300dre [or Phaedra]", "subcategory": "European Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Phe\u0300dre</u></b> [or <b><u>Phaedra</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Phe\u0300dre", "Phaedra"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "During the 16th century, this city founded four conservatories training young boys that became the model for public music schools throughout Europe. At one of those conservatories in this city, the castrato Farinelli studied under the singing teacher Nicola Porpora. Alessandro Gagliano (gah-lee-AH-no) led a family who made violins in this city, where round-backed mandolins originated in the 18th century. A school of opera composers named for this city included Giovanni Battista Pergolesi and Alessandro Scarlatti. This city is the setting of Mozart's Cosi fan tutte. A competition held during the Festival of Piedigrotta (pee-ay-dee-GROH-tah) inspired many of this city's songs, which were popularized by its native son Enrico Caruso. One of those songs from this city was written to commemorate the 3rst cable car on Mount Vesuvius, and is called \"Funiculi, Funicula.\" For 10 points, name this city home to the San Carlo opera house, whose popular songs include \"O Sole Mio.\"", "answer": "Naples [or Napoli; accept Neapolitan]", "subcategory": "Fine Arts European", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Naples</u></b> [or <b><u>Napoli</u></b>; accept <b><u>Neapolitan</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Naples", "Napoli", "Neapolitan"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In a book about \"design heuristics,\" Arthur Riel suggested that engineers at most only use this technique \"seven plus or minus two\" times when constructing hierarchies. The software engineer Steve McConnell recommended only using this technique when the Liskov Substitution Principle is not violated. This technique is disfavored for \"composition\" according to the composition reuse principle. In general, this technique is often used to follow the \"open-closed principle,\" which states that modules should be open for extension but closed for changes. \"Protected\" attributes can be accessed by objects created through this technique, but \"private\" ones cannot. Along with encapsulation and polymorphism, this technique is a key component of object-oriented programming. For 10 points, name this technique that allows computer programmers to create derived classes from base classes.", "answer": "inheritance [or inheriting; accept word forms; accept creating a derived class or word forms until \"derived\" is read; prompt on object-oriented programming or OOP until \"object-oriented\" is read]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>inheritance</u></b> [or <b><u>inheriting</u></b>;  accept word forms; accept <b><u>creating a derived class</u></b> or <b><u>word forms until \"derived\" is read</u></b>; prompt on <u>object-oriented programming</u> or <u>OOP until \"object-oriented\" is read</u>]", "acceptable": ["inheritance", "inheriting", "creating a derived class", "word forms until \"derived\" is read"], "promptable": ["object-oriented programming", "OOP until \"object-oriented\" is read"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A piece in this medium includes a depiction of a woman whose hair is overlaid with the colors magenta, cyan, and yellow and was the last completed work of Andy Warhol. In a Salvador Dali piece in this medium, a butter6ly-like 3gure atop a stick casts a shadow on a yellow monolithic rock. Alex Steinweiss is known as the father of this art form, which includes a Keith Haring depiction of two 3gures dancing in front of an orange background. Interactive works in this medium include a Robert Rauschenberg collage mash-up that changes as the viewer spins a color wheel and a Warhol work with a functioning zipper. One created by Robert Mapplethorpe depicts a dark-haired woman with a long black ribbon around her neck holding her jacket over her shoulder. Another of these works includes the text \"Peel slowly and see.\" For 10 points, name this medium, works in which include an Andy Warhol painting of a bright yellow banana.", "answer": "album covers [or cover art]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>album covers</u></b> [or <b><u>cover art</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["album covers", "cover art"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In an essay by this author, he recalled making and tearing up lists \"of cavalry leaders and football players and cities...and of women I'd liked, and of the times I had let myself be snubbed.\" In that essay, he compared himself to a plate that \"can never again be brought out for company, but it will do to hold crackers late at night.\" That essay of his proposes that \"the test of a 3rst-rate intelligence is the ability to hold two opposed ideas in the mind at the same time, and still retain the ability to function.\" In a novel by this author, the narrator recalls how he complimented a man he \"disapproved of...from beginning to end\" by shouting \"They're a rotten crowd...You're worth the whole damn bunch put together.\" In that novel by this author of The Crack-Up, the title character is shot in his swimming pool a7ter his yellow car is involved in a fatal hit-and-run in the Valley of Ashes. For 10 points, name this American author who created Nick Carraway in The Great Gatsby.", "answer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald [or Francis Scott Key Fitzgerald]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "F. Scott <b><u>Fitzgerald</u></b> [or <b><u>Francis Scott Key Fitzgerald</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["F. Scott Fitzgerald", "Francis Scott Key Fitzgerald"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Under the assumptions of uniformity, mutual variable independence, and pa\u00c2\u00b7ra\u00c2\u00b7met\u00c2\u00b7er\u00c2\u00b7ization redundancy, this system's spherically constrained Hamiltonian is equivalent to the loss function of a fully decoupled large-size neural network. A procedure originally developed to compute the ground states of this system relies on the mathematical formula that \"the natural logarithm of a variable Z\" equals \"the limit as n goes to zero\" of \"minus one plus Z to the n,\" all divided by \"n.\" Giorgio Parisi used that \"replica trick\" to solve this system under the mean 3eld approximation. This system undergoes non-exponential decay of the re\u00c2\u00b7ma\u00c2\u00b7nent magnetization below its transition temperature a7ter the removal of all external magnetic 3elds. For 10 points, name this system that exhibits quenched disorder leading to geometrical frustration, and can be represented as a lattice of randomly aligned magnetic dipoles.", "answer": "spin glasses [or Sherrington-Kirkpatrick model; prompt on glasses or Ising model]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>spin glasses</u></b> [or <b><u>Sherrington-Kirkpatrick model</u></b>; prompt on <u>glasses</u> or <u>Ising model</u>]", "acceptable": ["spin glasses", "Sherrington-Kirkpatrick model"], "promptable": ["glasses", "Ising model"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In The Old Curiosity Shop, Nell and her grandfather are taken in by a man of this profession named Mr. Marton. Another of them disguises himself as Rogue Riderhood to try to drown Eugene Wrayburn, his rival for the love of Lizzie Hexam. Bradley Headstone in Our Mutual Friend shares this profession with a man who remains convinced of the faithfulness of his much younger wife Annie, despite the insinuations of Uriah Heep. Another character with this profession is a one-eyed Yorkshire man who is beaten by his employee Nicholas Nickleby a7ter himself beating Smike. Another of them, who has children named Malthus and Adam Smith, realizes his extreme fact-based approach to this profession is 6lawed when his daughter Louisa confesses her unhappy marriage to Josiah Bounderby. For 10 points, name this profession shared by many Charles Dickens characters, including Dr. Strong from David Copper3eld, Wackford Squeers from Nicholas Nickleby, and Thomas Gradgrind from Hard Times.", "answer": "schoolmaster [or schoolteacher; or headmaster; or schoolboard superintendant; or tutor; or educator; prompt on scholar]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>schoolmaster</u></b> [or <b><u>schoolteacher</u></b>; or <b><u>headmaster</u></b>; or <b><u>schoolboard superintendant</u></b>; or <b><u>tutor</u></b>; or <b><u>educator</u></b>; prompt on <u>scholar</u>]", "acceptable": ["schoolmaster", "schoolteacher", "headmaster", "schoolboard superintendant", "tutor", "educator"], "promptable": ["scholar"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Jonathan Winkler's Nexus explains how the a7termath of this event led to unprecedented integration of private business and government research, while Nicholas Lambert argued that its protagonists were unwilling to threaten their own economic networks. It's not the Holocaust, but Arno Mayer (MY-ur) interpreted this event in light of what he called the \"Primacy of Domestic Politics.\" A very stupid book by Max Hastings rea53rmed the \"Fischer School\" explanations for this event, which Niall (neel) Ferguson counterfactually imagined leading to an earlier emergence of continental union. Traditional explanations of the cause of this event were rejected in Christopher Clark's The Sleepwalkers. Literary culture lacked the ability to accurately re6lect this event until the rise of Modernist irony according to Paul Fussell, who examined this event along with \"modern memory.\" For 10 points, name this war whose causes are treated in Barbara Tuchman's The Guns of August.", "answer": "World War I [accept equivalents such as WWI, The Great War, The War to End All Wars, etc.]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>World War I</u></b> [accept <b><u>equivalents such as WWI, The Great War, The War to End All Wars, etc.</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["World War I", "equivalents such as WWI, The Great War, The War to End All Wars, etc."], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Terry Bouton argues that the rate of this action eclipsed 37ty percent for many Pennsylvania counties in the decade a7ter the Revolutionary War, pursuant to a deliberate state-building project. Congress introduced a 5-year waiting period as a prerequisite to certain instances of this action in the Frazier-Lemke Act. The story of a cancer nurse, a car dealership worker, and an insurance fraud specialist uncovering fraudulent instances of this action is told in a 2016 David Dayen book. Merle Hansen led an organization that resisted this action during the Great Depression by intimidating people during \"penny auctions.\" Critics claim that organizations like MERS have facilitated this action on an industrial scale with the practice of \"robo-signing.\" Residents evicted from the Umoja Village shantytown in Miami took advantage of Florida's crippling high rate for this action during a 2010 crisis, whose fallout forced Bank of America and others to put a freeze on many instances of this action. For 10 points, identify this action in which debt defaults lead to the seizure of one's farm or home.", "answer": "foreclosure [or repossession; prompt on bankruptcy or loan-default]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>foreclosure</u></b> [or <b><u>repossession</u></b>; prompt on <u>bankruptcy</u> or <u>loan-default</u>]", "acceptable": ["foreclosure", "repossession"], "promptable": ["bankruptcy", "loan-default"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Brian Loar's critique of this argument opens by citing the Frenchman Pierre in Saul Kripke's \"A Puzzle About Belief.\" In The Conscious Mind, David Chalmers replies directly to this argument by proposing a two-by-two matrix whose diagonal and top row encode primary and secondary intensions. This argument was modi3ed by Tyler Burge, whose paper \"Other Bodies\" discusses a woman named Jane with arthritis in her thigh. The classic statement of this argument appears alongside a discussion of the di5ference between elms and beeches and states two Fregean (FRAY-gee-an) principles it 3nds fallacious. That statement of this argument takes place in the year 1750, before modern chemistry, and concludes that meaning \"just ain't in the head\" because \"water\" means both H2O and XYZ. For 10 points, name this thought experiment 3rst proposed by Hilary Putnam which involves a planet super3cially identical to our own.", "answer": "Twin Earth thought experiment [or semantic externalism argument]", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Twin Earth thought experiment</u></b> [or <b><u>semantic externalism argument</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Twin Earth thought experiment", "semantic externalism argument"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "[missing]", "answer": "[missing]", "answer_formatted": "<b><u></u></b> [missing]", "acceptable": [""], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Richard Kohn's article on \"The Inside Story\" of this event argues that it was largely stage-managed to bolster the case for central government. The genesis of this event lay in the organizing of men like Matthias Ogden and Alexander McDougall, who helped bring it about by sending a letter signed \"Brutus.\" Dissatisfied participants in this event may have organized a march two months later that caused a series of rapid relocations to Princeton, Annapolis, and Trenton. It followed the rejection of an impost amendment supported by its possible real organizers, Robert Morris and Alexander Hamilton. At the climax of this event, one man affected difficulty in putting on his spectacles as a reminder of his service. This event was preceded by a Lewis Nicola letter requesting that its recipient declare himself a monarch, and ended after a speech in an assembly tent to a group of men including John Armstrong and Horatio Gates. A short but powerful speech by George Washington mollified, for 10 points, what \"conspiracy\" by colonial officers angry over back pay?", "answer": "The Newburgh Conspiracy", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Newburgh Conspiracy</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The Newburgh Conspiracy"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An enzyme in this pathway is also used in the last step of a fermentation process developed by Chaim Weizmann. That enzyme from this pathway has an active site lysine whose pKa (\"p-K-a\") is altered to be 4.5 units below its normal value. Activation of this pathway is the preferred treatment for pediatric epilepsy. Leucine and lysine are the only two amino acids that are exclusively metabolized via this pathway. Its products can be identi3ed in urine by a pink color on nitro-prusside sticks. Kussmaul breathing is triggered by activation of this pathway in diabetics. When glucose is unavailable, neurons can use its products as energy sources; those products include beta hydroxy-butyrate, which lacks its namesake functional group. For 10 points, name this fasting pathway that converts fatty acids into molecules like acetone, activated by diets like the Atkins.", "answer": "ketogenesis [accept ketosis, ketoacidosis, or ketone body synthesis or production]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>ketogenesis</u></b> [accept <b><u>ketosis, ketoacidosis,</u></b> or <b><u>ketone body synthesis</u></b> or <b><u>production</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["ketogenesis", "ketosis, ketoacidosis,", "ketone body synthesis", "production"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The generation of ethylene gas from this molecule is used to assess nitrogenase activity in an ARA assay. Shirakawa, MacDiarmid and Heeger won the 2000 Nobel Prize in Chemistry for synthesizing a conducting polymer of this molecule. The classic example of a template reaction is this compound's cyclo-oligomerization to cyclo-octa-tetra-ene. Cyanogen can be produced when this molecule and nitrogen are reacted in the presence of a spark. A metallo cyclopentadiene intermediate occurs in a 2+2+2 [\"two plus two plus two\"] trimerization of this molecule to form benzene. Walter Reppe pioneered studies of its reactivity. Hydroboration-oxidation of this molecule results in acetaldehyde. It has two hydrogens with pKa's [\"p-k-aze\"] of 25. Arc welding has largely replaced welding that used this molecule as a fuel source. For 10 points, name this simplest alkyne.", "answer": "acetylene [or ethyne; or C2H2]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>acetylene</u></b> [or <b><u>ethyne</u></b>; or <b><u>C2H2</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["acetylene", "ethyne", "C2H2"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In ancient art, many statues of a divinity whose head has been replaced with a pot of 6lowers will show honey 6lowing or lotuses blooming from one of these things. Five downward pointing triangles--and not the four-upward pointing ones--that comprise the Sri Yantra diagram represent the power of these things in Tantric systems. A 3ssure which has been 3lled with groundwater and represents one of them is the holiest part of the Kamakhya (kah-MAHK-yah) Temple in Assam. The name for the innermost sanctum of Hindu temples, garbhagriha (garb-hah-gree-hah), literally means the \"house of\" this thing. Depictions of the deities Lajja Gauri and Sakhambari (lah-jah gow-ree and sahk-hahm-bah-ree) o7ten highlight these things, which are represented as the horizontal base on which lingams--their counterparts--are placed. For 10 points, name these organs called yoni, which are revered as the feminine source of life in Hinduism.", "answer": "wombs [or vaginas; accept yoni before \"yoni\"; accept gharbha before \"garbhagriha\"]", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>wombs</u></b> [or <b><u>vaginas</u></b>; accept <b><u>yoni</u></b> before \"yoni; accept <b><u>gharbha</u></b> before \"garbhagriha]", "acceptable": ["wombs", "vaginas", "yoni", "gharbha"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Anthony Caro painted steel this color for a sculpture he titled for the time it was 3nished, Early One Morning. White cables stretch out from a lightbulb in a room otherwise entirely this color in a pioneering color photograph by William Eggleston set in Mississippi. Kazimir Malevich represented a \"peasant woman in two dimensions\" with a painting of a non-black square of this color. A 2009 exhibit at the Royal Academy consisted of a cannon 3ring globs of waxy paint of this color; that exhibit's creator also designed a set of three steel hoops connected by a membrane of this color for Turbine Hall. At 140 Broadway, a tilted steel cube painted this color with a cylindrical hole through it was designed by Isamu Noguchi. Many sculptures by Anish Kapoor, such as Marsyas, use intense shades of this color, which also dominates a \"stabile\" outside Chicago's Willis Tower. For 10 points, name this color of Robert Indiana's Love sculpture and the cherry in Claes Oldenburg's Spoonbridge and Cherry.", "answer": "red [or shades of red, such as vermilion]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>red</u></b> [or <b><u>shades of red, such as vermilion</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["red", "shades of red, such as vermilion"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A7ter leaving four years of monastic life, this historical person annually made a grand feast with an older lover on the seventh day of the seventh lunar month. Legendarily, this person was thought to have 6led to an eastern paradise at Penglai (pung-\"lie\") or to Japan, which may have inspired Japanese depictions of this person as Avalokitesvara (ah-vah-loh-kee-tesh-vah-rah). This person, whose story is told in \"The Song of Everlasting Sorrow,\" is the title character of Kenji Mizoguchi's 3lm Yokihi. This person was strangled to death in a temple courtyard a7ter a scheme in which Tibetan diplomats plotted with this person's cousin Guozhong (gwo-jong) to take over the palace. An ability to easily 6latter the emperor and this person was widely credited for the promotion of Geshu Han's main rival, a Sogdian general. For 10 points, name this \"Precious Consort\" of Emperor Xuanzong (shwan-zohng) of Tang, a member of the Four Beauties who was widely blamed for the An Lushan rebellion.", "answer": "Yang Guifei [or Yang Yuhuan; or Taizhen; or Imperial Consort Yang; or Yokihi until it is read]", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "Yang <b><u>Guifei</u></b> [or <b><u>Yang Yuhuan</u></b>; or <b><u>Taizhen</u></b>; or <b><u>Imperial Consort Yang</u></b>; or <b><u>Yokihi until it is read</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Yang Guifei", "Yang Yuhuan", "Taizhen", "Imperial Consort Yang", "Yokihi until it is read"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The political psychology of Murray Edelman focuses on the role these entities play in politics. Paul Tillich characterized these entities as \"double-edged\" since they have both \"transcendent\" and \"immanent\" components. David Schneider's studies of American kinship originated the idea of \"core\" ones. The four-quadrant \"grid-group\" diagram was introduced in a book on \"natural\" ones by Mary Douglas. A distinction between \"discursive\" and \"presentational\" categories of these entities was made by Susanne Langer. Muchona the Hornet's testimony on the Mudyi tree provided material for an analysis of these entities among the Ndembu. Victor Turner wrote about the \"forest\" of these constructs, whose relation to \"man\" was documented in a book by Carl Jung. For 10 points, name these means of communication, which are signs that represent other concepts.", "answer": "symbols", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>symbols</u></b>", "acceptable": ["symbols"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to legend, this region's 6lag was created when Charles the Bald dipped his 3ngers in its count's blood and drew four lines on his shield. Irregular 3ghters called \"little Michaels\" resisted the Duke of Noailles' (noh-\"eye\"-yuh's) invading army in this region's theater of the Nine Years' War. It codi3ed a class of unfree peasants named a7ter the practice of redemptio under its medieval law, the \"Usages.\" In response to the Union of Arms, peasants from this region murdered a royalist duke during Corpus Christi to start its 3rst national uprising. Wilfred the Hairy is the traditional founder of this region, whose anthem tells the \"defenders of the land\" to \"strike with [their] sickle\" in memory of its \"Reapers' War.\" The 1714 Nueva Planta decrees ordered the dissolution of its parliament, the Generalitat, and the replacement of its traditional language with Castilian. For 10 points, name this autonomous community of Spain with a powerful separatist movement.", "answer": "Catalonia [or Catalunya]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Catalonia</u></b> [or <b><u>Catalunya</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Catalonia", "Catalunya"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Changes to this system were compared to attempts to \"clean the air on one side of a screen door\" by Jean Anyon (jeen ann-yon), whose major book critiques those attempts for neglecting embeddedness. This system commissioned a controversial $3 million algorithm designed by the Parthenon Group, and protesters against changes to this system circulated photographs of the \"Enlightenment of Man\" mural. Cami Anderson played a controversial role in administering this system, which has been under state rather than city control since 1995. A bloated bureaucracy where \"even some clerks had clerks\" was blamed for its pro6ligate spending in Dale Roussako5f's The Prize, which chronicled a reform e5fort announced on the Oprah Winfrey Show. Ras Baraka was elected mayor for opposing reforms to this program funded by a $100 million gi7t by Mark Zuckerberg. For 10 points, name this school system that underwent controversial reforms championed by Mayor Cory Booker.", "answer": "Newark Public School System [or anything mentioning Newark Schools, including Newark Charter Schools; prompt on answers mentioning New Jersey or United States Public Schools]", "category": "Current Events", "subcategory": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Newark Public School System</u></b> [or <b><u>anything mentioning Newark Schools, including Newark Charter Schools</u></b>; prompt on <u>answers mentioning New Jersey</u> or <u>United States Public Schools</u>]", "acceptable": ["Newark Public School System", "anything mentioning Newark Schools, including Newark Charter Schools"], "promptable": ["answers mentioning New Jersey", "United States Public Schools"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Grant Allen essay \"Seven-Year Sleepers\" describes a snail that miraculously came back to life in this building. Alfred Hitchcock used a predecessor of bluescreen, the Schu57tan process, to set parts of 1929's Blackmail in this building. In 2015, it became the largest indoor space on Google Street View. The facade of this building was designed by Robert Smirke and was based on the temple of Athene Polias at Priene. A David Lodge novel about a single day in Adam Appleby's life is titled for this building \"Falling Down.\" Enoch Soames trades his soul for an opportunity to spend an a7ternoon in this building, which houses the Lewis Chessmen and a series of reliefs depicting an Assyrian Lion Hunt. Its best-known artifact was discovered by Jean-Franc\u0327ois Champollion (shahm-poh-lee-ohn) and features text in Egyptian, Demotic and Ancient Greek. For 10 points, name this national museum home to the Rosetta Stone, located in London.", "answer": "The British Museum", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The British Museum</u></b>", "acceptable": ["The British Museum"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}